Aleksander Prifti

2N Horncastle Road, London SE12 9LA +44 07476148435

prifti.aleksandri@gmail.com

Profile

I am a front-end software developer with great passion for learning new technologies and applications. Strong consulting skills accrued professionally and strong academic background thanks to postgraduate studies in Technology, Innovation and Entrepreneurship. Experience in front-end development using technologies such as HTML5 - CSS3 - JavaScript - jQuery. My curiosity for responsive web design and development drive my interest on learning new technologies such as CSS framework Bootstrap. Last but not least, working with relational databases, Oracle databases, using SQL for querying and maintaining the database is another achievement through my carrier. Becoming a full-stack developer is not only my main goal but also a way to release my potential as a software developer.

Career Summary

11/2017 – 12/2017

Layer 9, London

BI/ETL Developer/Data Visualization

- Receiving training on Pentaho (big data integration and analytic solutions)
- Learning Data Warehouse concepts and SQL development.
- Exposure on real client projects
- Working with PDI (Pentaho Data Integration) a visualisation tool for big data

07/2012 - 07/2017

Facilization LTD, Tirana

Development Team/Consultant Banking Applications

Development Team:

I have been part of the development team, cross working with business analyst team in several web-based applications for the financial sector and not only. Main project that I was actively involved is 'FaciliLegal' which is a full-fledged application dedicated to banks, dealing with debt collections and collateral recovery process. My responsibilities:

- Working with development team for the release of the new upgraded version using technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, SQL. I have built the login screen with new features and also making modification regarding UX/UI making the applications friendlier for users.
- Gathering technical specifications
- Requirement validation and Test Plan Preparation
- Customer specific customization
- On site meetings participation
- Managing 'Freshdesk' support ticketing system for the company

Consultant:

Working as a consultant for a range of products developed by Facilization. The package include a series of applications addressing various business needs such in the areas of legal, information and transaction processing, real time transaction toward utility services providers for bank customers as a result reducing payment process. Nevertheless, consulting process was closely related to development phase where I was able to provide my contribution in UI/UX process. Working with front-end technologies HTML4/CSS3/JS. New and upgraded versions of products were constantly released as a result I was an active member of development team.

Oracle Flexcube:

Onsite support for client based in Malta. Working with Oracel Database 11g. The client, Pilatus Bank an exclusive and private bank based in Malta with clients across the world. After the successful implementation of Oracle Flexcube, which offers a full coverage of mobile banking applications and a complete range for corporate and private banking functionality, my task was to assist the client in everyday usage of Flexcube and also report any kind of issues directly to Oracle Support Platform. My responsibilities:

- Executing queries on Oracel Database 11g using SQL
- Assisting the staff of the bank during day to day transactions
- Reporting any kind of issue by using Oracle Support Platform
- Using test environment for patch deployment before implementation to live applications
- Controlling End-Of-Day/End-of-Month process of the bank

02/2009 - 06/2012

Intesa Sanpaolo Bank, Thessaloniki Branch

Assistant Branch Manger

Working as an assistant branch manager was a position that required technical and managerial skills. Oracle Flexcube was the core banking system used by the bank. Process such as account opening throw incoming/outgoing transactions were some of activities performed in a daily basis. Working with Oracle Database using SQL was a prerequisite for this position. My responsibilities:

- Working with Oracle Database using SQL
- Working with Flexcube Core Banking System
- Enforce dual control procedures at all times
- Maintain monthly branch efficiency logs
- Keep staff informed of pertinent changes in operational policy and procedures
- Keep educated on all deposit, business, and consumer loan products
- Facilitate teller buys and sells to the vault

Career Summary cont.

04/2007 - 02/2009

Intesa Sanpaolo Bank, Thessaloniki Branch

Marketing

The role was a combination of technical skills and marketing development process. Regarding the technical aspect I had the responsibility to retrieve useful information from Oracle DB using SQL, and then all these amounts of information was used to develop new marketing strategies and new products. I was part of a bigger and qualified team composed of database administrator and developer. Data retrieval using mostly SELECT statement, displaying data from multiple table were some of my day to day tasks along with:

- Producing reports from Oracle DB using SQL
- Bank website content editing and maintenance
- Developing new Marketing Strategies
- Promoting banking products and services

Education

2007 – 2009 Postgraduate diploma in Technology, Innovation and Entrepreneurship

University Of Sheffield

- · Developing practical innovative skills
- Learn strategies to identify the root causes of current issue
- How to communicate complex ideas to a broad audience
- Relationship between innovation, business and technology

2005 – 2007 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Sheffield

- Software Engineering, Database Systems
- Operating Systems
- OOP (Java), Web Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL)

Competencies

Communication: Good communication skills gained from my experience in banking sector, everyday interaction with quite a

considerable number of clients. Working on several projects it was also a point of reference for acquiring good

communication skills.

Managerial: In the context of managerial skills, I was responsible for a team of 3 people working in 2 different projects. During my

working carrier I have also been responsible for several small-scale projects.

Job-related: Developing new business ideas, thus preparing business plans on business proposals. Also, I have been involved is

several projects related to web development such as websites and web applications. In the course of my job experience I have worked with technologies such as: HTML5 - CSS3 – Javascript – jQuery – SQL – MySql – Git & Github

- Bootstrap - Balsamiq Wireframe

Languages: Native/Bilingual in Greek and Albanian. Fluent in English and Italian

Interests: Been updated regarding new software development in automobile industry is one my interests. Play basketball a lot,

and I consider myself quite good at it. Also, football is one of my favourite games

Achievements

From: 01-Sep-2017 "Full Stack Web Developer" course from 'Code Institute' credit rated by Edinburgh Napier University, making it the only accredited coding boot camp in Europe. The course is about maximising my skills as a full stack developer. It is an intensive coding course with the latest industry language. During the course I will have completed 4 projects that will be hosted on GitHub. In addition I will be awarded with a diploma "Diploma in Software Development" equivalent to European Qualifications Framework Level 5 that is globally recognized. Subject Overview • HTML5 • CSS3 • GitHub • Python – Django Framework • MongoDB • JavaScript • jQuery • Data Analytics • Version Control